<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kelvin Lin</title>
    <link>https://kelvinlin.ca/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Kelvin Lin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 23:04:27 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kelvinlin.ca/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Create a Master Plan for Your Double Degree</title>
      <link>https://kelvinlin.ca/blog/how-to-create-a-master-plan-for-your-double-degree/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 23:04:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kelvinlin.ca/blog/how-to-create-a-master-plan-for-your-double-degree/</guid>
      <description>Once you&amp;rsquo;ve received the go-ahead from your academic advisor, it is time to start planning out your McMaster double degrees. When planning your degrees, start with the end goal in mind. Ask yourself what you would like to have achieved by graduation. Starting with the end goal in mind ensure that you take the most appropriate courses for your degrees (and have the proper prerequisite courses to enroll in upper-year classes), so you can get the most out of your journey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Talk to Your Academic Advisors about Your Double Degree</title>
      <link>https://kelvinlin.ca/blog/how-to-talk-to-your-academic-advisors-about-your-double-degree/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 22:34:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kelvinlin.ca/blog/how-to-talk-to-your-academic-advisors-about-your-double-degree/</guid>
      <description>Source: Unsplash
Navigating university bureaucracy can be a daunting task given all the different levels of authority that are responsible for administering a degree program. Luckily, the academic advisors at McMaster are more than happy to provide you with advice to help you complete your double degree. It is important to speak with an academic advisor once you have chosen majors for your double degree in order to find out more about the permissibility of your major combination (not all combinations of majors are allowed) as well as clarify any misconceptions you may have about the relevant policies surrounding your majors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Choose Your Double Degree Majors</title>
      <link>https://kelvinlin.ca/blog/how-to-choose-your-double-degree-majors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 21:48:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kelvinlin.ca/blog/how-to-choose-your-double-degree-majors/</guid>
      <description>Source: Unsplash
Choosing your major can be one of the most important yet stressful decisions you make during your undergraduate career. Your majors will dictate the courses you need to take, the academic policies you need to follow, and what your transcripts and degrees will list when you graduate. Doing a double degree means you have (at least) twice as many majors - but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be twice as stressful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Get a Double Degree at McMaster University</title>
      <link>https://kelvinlin.ca/blog/how-to-get-a-double-degree-at-mcmaster-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 18:43:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kelvinlin.ca/blog/how-to-get-a-double-degree-at-mcmaster-university/</guid>
      <description>Source: Unsplash
Getting a double degree at McMaster isn&amp;rsquo;t easy. Double degrees (otherwise known as concurrent second bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degrees) are not formally defined by the university, very few students pursue double degrees, and the onus is ultimately on you to determine the path you need to take in order to successfully complete all of the degree requirements.
Having recently graduated with concurrent double degrees in Software Engineering &amp;amp; Management as well as Economics, I hope to create a blog to help others do the same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://kelvinlin.ca/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 16:25:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kelvinlin.ca/contact/</guid>
      <description>  
Want to contact me? Email me at linkk4 (at) mcmaster.ca, send me a message on LinkedIn, or fill out the form below, and I&amp;rsquo;ll get back to you as soon as I can.
Loading... </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy</title>
      <link>https://kelvinlin.ca/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 16:25:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kelvinlin.ca/privacy/</guid>
      <description>1. General Policy Your privacy is important to me. It is my policy to respect your privacy regarding any information I may collect from you across my website, https://kelvinlin.ca.
I only ask for personal information when we truly need it to provide a service to you. I collect it by fair and lawful means, with your knowledge and consent. I also let you know why I&amp;rsquo;m collecting it and how it will be used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses</title>
      <link>https://kelvinlin.ca/courses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 17:23:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kelvinlin.ca/courses/</guid>
      <description> McMaster University The following is a list of courses that I&amp;rsquo;ve taken at McMaster University.
  
Commerce (12 courses)   Course Code Course Name     COMMERCE 4QA3 Operations Modelling and Analysis   COMMERCE 4PA3 Business Policy: Strategic Management   COMMERCE 4MI3 Marketing Analytics   COMMERCE 4KG3 Data Mining and Business Intelligence   COMMERCE 3MC3 Applied Marketing Management   COMMERCE 3FA3 Managerial Finance   COMMERCE 2MA3 Introduction to Marketing   COMMERCE 2FA3 Introduction to Finance   COMMERCE 2BC3 Human Resource Management and Labour Relations   COMMERCE 2AB3 Managerial Accounting I   COMMERCE 1BA3 Organizational Behaviour   COMMERCE 1AA3 Introductory Financial Accounting      Computer Science (2 courses)   Course Code Course Name     COMPSCI 4O03 Linear Optimization   COMPSCI 4ML3 Introduction to Machine Learning      Economics (8 courses)   Course Code Course Name     ECON 3M03 Introduction to Game Theory   ECON 3E03 Applied Econometrics   ECON 2X03 Applied Business Economics   ECON 2HH3 Intermediate Macroeconomics II   ECON 2H03 Intermediate Macroeconomics I   ECON 2GG3 Intermediate Microeconomics II   ECON 1BB3 Introductory Macroeconomics   ECON 1B03 Introductory Microeconomics      Engineering and Management (3 courses)   Course Code Course Name     ENGNMGT 5B03 Engineering and Management Projects   ENGNMGT 4A03 Innovation Driven Project Development and Management   ENGNMGT 2AA2 Communication Skills      General Engineering (4 courses)   Course Code Course Name     ENGINEER 4A03 Sustainability and Ethics in Engineering   ENGINEER 1P03 Engineering Profession and Practice   ENGINEER 1D04 Engineering Computation   ENGINEER 1C03 Engineering Design and Graphics      General Sciences (6 courses)   Course Code Course Name     WHMIS 1A00 Introduction to Health and Safety   PHYSICS 1E03 Waves, Electricity, and Magnetic Fields   PHYSICS 1D03 Introductory Mechanics   MATLS 1M03 Structure and Properties of Materials   ENVIRSC 1C03 Climate, Water, and Environment   CHEM 1E03 General Chemistry for Enigneering I      Mathematics (5 courses)   Course Code Course Name     MATH 2ZZ3 Engineering Mathematics IV   MATH 2Z03 Engineering Mathematics III   MATH 1ZC3 Engineering Mathematics II - Part B   MATH 1ZB3 Engineering Mathematics II - Part A   MATH 1ZA3 Engineering Mathematics I      Software Enigneering (24 courses)   Course Code Course Name     SFWRENG 4X03 Scientific Computation   SFWRENG 4TE3 Continuous Optimization Algorithms   SFWRENG 4HC3 Human Computer Interfaces   SFWRENG 4G06 Software Design IV - Capstone Design Project   SFWRENG 4F03 Parallel Computing   SFWRENG 4C03 Computer Networks and Security   SFWRENG 4AA4 Real-Time Systems and Control Applications   SFWRENG 3XA3 Software Engineering Practice and Experience: Software Project Management   SFWRENG 3S03 Software Testing   SFWRENG 3RA3 Software Requirements and Security Considerations   SFWRENG 3MX3 Signals and Systems   SFWRENG 3DX4 Dynamic Systems and Control   SFWRENG 3DB3 Databases   SFWRENG 3BB4 Software Design II - Concurrent System Design   SFWRENG 3A04 Software Design III - Large System Design   SFWRENG 2XB3 Software Engineering Practice and Experience: Binding Theory to Practice   SFWRENG 2XA3 Software Engineering Practice and Experience: Software Development Skills   SFWRENG 2S03 Principles of Programming   SFWRENG 2GA3 Computer Architecture   SFWRENG 2FA3 Discrete Mathematics with Applications II   SFWRENG 2DM3 Discrete Mathematics with Applications I   SFWRENG 2DA4 Digital Systems and Interfacing   SFWRENG 2C03 Data Structures and Algorithms   SFWRENG 2AA4 Software Design I - Introduction to Software Development      Software Technology (2 courses)   Course Code Course Name     SFWRTECH 4DM3 Data Mining   SFWRTECH 4DA3 Data Analytics and Big Data      Statistics (2 courses)   Course Code Course Name     STATS 3Y03 Probability and Statistics for Engineering   STATS 2D03 Introduction to Probability      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awards and Certificates</title>
      <link>https://kelvinlin.ca/awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 16:23:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kelvinlin.ca/awards/</guid>
      <description>Here are a selection of awards and certificates that I&amp;rsquo;ve received from work, school, and participating in programming and engineering competitions.
MOOCs (3 certificates) Artificial Intelligence Nanodegree    School: Udacity My AI nanodegree covered probabilistic AI, game-playing agents, search algorithms, neural networks, deep learning, and a specialization in NLP. The syllabus for this nanodegree can be found here.    M101J: MongoDB for Java Developers    School: MongoDB University M101J covered topics such as no-SQL databases, MongoDB&#39;s document model and basic schema design, MongoDB CRUD operations, and how to read and write to a MongoDB database using Java.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://kelvinlin.ca/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 18:15:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kelvinlin.ca/projects/</guid>
      <description>Here are some projects that I am proud to have worked on. Other projects can be found on my Github at: https://github.com/KelvinKKLin. Project Imacs    A non-linear text editor/file visualization tool created for my Software Engineering capstone at McMaster University - Recieved A+.
Technologies Used: HTML/CSS, TypeScript, Electron, D3, Hyperapp    Parallel N-Body Simulator    A n-particle physics simulator that models the interaction between up to 32,000 particles in empty space - Received A+.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://kelvinlin.ca/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 14:44:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kelvinlin.ca/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello world, I&amp;rsquo;m Kelvin - a recent Software Engineering, Management, and Economics double-degree graduate from McMaster University. I LOVE creating impactful software systems that make the world a better place and empowering others to do the same using technology. More details about my work experiences and qualifications can be found on LinkedIn at: https://linkedin.com/in/kelvin-lin. 
Education See Courses  Bachelor of Engineering and Management in Software Engineering and Management (Co-op)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>