<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kelvin Lin</title>
    <link>https://kelvinlin.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Kelvin Lin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Kelvin Lin © 2022</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 08:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kelvinlin.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>100 Days of HAM</title>
      <link>https://kelvinlin.com/hobby/100daysofham/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kelvinlin.com/hobby/100daysofham/</guid>
      <description>This page tracks my progress for the 100 days of HAM challenge.
Between December 18th, 2022 and March 28th, 2023, I will spend 1 hour everyday to learn about HAM radio. I will work towards preparing for the Amateur Radio Service licensing exams, and learning how to operate a radio. I am doing this because I am interested in communication technologies, and I think radio is a cool alternative to the internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Graduate from McMaster University</title>
      <link>https://kelvinlin.com/blog/how-to-graduate-from-mcmaster-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 10:42:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kelvinlin.com/blog/how-to-graduate-from-mcmaster-university/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered what it would be like to walk down the stage during the McMaster Convocation ceremony? Do you want to know ALL the details? Perhaps you want to plan ahead? Earlier this May, I graduated twice from McMaster (with a B.Eng.Mgt in Software Engineering and Management Co-op and a B.A. in Economics), and in this blog post, I will describe my graduation experience so you can be prepared when your time comes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Participate in Extracurricular Activities</title>
      <link>https://kelvinlin.com/blog/how-to-participate-in-extracurricular-activities/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 11:02:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kelvinlin.com/blog/how-to-participate-in-extracurricular-activities/</guid>
      <description>University is not just about studying. In order to thrive at McMaster, it is essential that you find a good balance between academics, extracurricular activities, and your personal life. As a double degree student, clubs and teams offer a unique opportunity for you to integrate your knowledge of two or more disciplines in real-world scenarios, but it also presents the additional challenge of managing a heavy schedule. In my previous posts, I discussed how to excel in the academic side of pursuing a double degree.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COMPSCI 4ML3: An Honest Review</title>
      <link>https://kelvinlin.com/blog/compsci-4ml3-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 22:48:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kelvinlin.com/blog/compsci-4ml3-review/</guid>
      <description>I recently completed McMaster&amp;rsquo;s inaugural offering of COMPSCI 4ML3: Introduction to Machine Learning taught by Dr. Hassan Ashtiani. Motivated by my enthusiasm for machine learning as well as lack of reviews of this course, I wanted to write a quick blog post to describe my experience in this course for students who are looking to take this course in the future.
An example of an artificial neural network, one of the algorithms discussed in COMPSCI 4ML3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Honest Thoughts on McMaster Engineering&#39;s Co-op Program</title>
      <link>https://kelvinlin.com/blog/3-honest-thoughts-on-mcmasters-coop-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 10:38:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kelvinlin.com/blog/3-honest-thoughts-on-mcmasters-coop-program/</guid>
      <description>The Engineering Co-op and Internship program at McMaster University provides an amazing opportunity for students to test drive potential careers, apply skills learned in class to real-world problems, and to build their professional network. Having recently completed McMaster&amp;rsquo;s Engineering Co-op program, I would like to share 3 pieces of advice I have to help you land your dream co-op placement.
OscarPlus - McMaster Engineering&amp;rsquo;s Co-op Portal: https://oscarplusmcmaster.ca.
Note that I am not an academic advisor, nor do I hold/have held any positions at McMaster that would qualify me to provide professional academic advice on behalf of the university.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Enroll in Courses at McMaster University: Part 2</title>
      <link>https://kelvinlin.com/blog/how-to-enroll-in-courses-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 22:19:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kelvinlin.com/blog/how-to-enroll-in-courses-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, it is difficult if not impossible to create your perfect timetable using McMaster&amp;rsquo;s My Timetable tool. Perhaps you need to overload to graduate with your double degree on time. Or maybe you need to take a course that you are missing prerequisites for. Regardless of the reason, if you find McMaster&amp;rsquo;s My Timetable tool unsatisfactory, then you can manually create your own timetable using the 5 steps I will describe in this blog post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Enroll in Courses at McMaster University: Part 1</title>
      <link>https://kelvinlin.com/blog/how-to-enroll-in-courses-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 11:06:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kelvinlin.com/blog/how-to-enroll-in-courses-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Now that you know what courses you need to graduate with a double degree, it is time to start planning out your next semester. Over the next 2 blog posts, I will introduce 2 different ways for you to plan your timetable so that it fits your needs. In this first short blog post, I will introduce the McMaster My Timetable tool that will automatically generate timetables for you to choose from given a list of courses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Honest Thoughts on McMaster&#39;s Software Engineering and Management Program</title>
      <link>https://kelvinlin.com/blog/3-honest-thoughts-on-mcmasters-software-engineering-and-management-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 23:10:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kelvinlin.com/blog/3-honest-thoughts-on-mcmasters-software-engineering-and-management-program/</guid>
      <description>A couple of days ago, McMaster released degree program placements to incoming second-year students, which will determine the course of study for many students for the remainder of their degree (unless the student decides to transfer or pursue a double degree). This is a time filled with excitement, worry, anticipation, and perhaps disappointment, but seeing as there are very few reviews of the Software Engineering and Management (Co-op) program that I recently graduated from, I have decided to start a blog series documenting my own personal thoughts on the program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Create a Master Plan for Your Double Degree</title>
      <link>https://kelvinlin.com/blog/how-to-create-a-master-plan-for-your-double-degree/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 23:04:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kelvinlin.com/blog/how-to-create-a-master-plan-for-your-double-degree/</guid>
      <description>Once you&amp;rsquo;ve received the go-ahead from your academic advisor, it is time to start planning out your McMaster double degree. When planning your degrees, start with the end goal in mind. Ask yourself what you would like to have achieved by graduation. Starting with the end goal in mind ensures that you will take the most appropriate courses for your degrees (and have the proper prerequisite courses to enroll in upper-year classes), so you can get the most out of your double degree journey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Talk to Your Academic Advisors about Your Double Degree</title>
      <link>https://kelvinlin.com/blog/how-to-talk-to-your-academic-advisors-about-your-double-degree/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 22:34:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kelvinlin.com/blog/how-to-talk-to-your-academic-advisors-about-your-double-degree/</guid>
      <description>Source: Unsplash.
Navigating university bureaucracy can be a daunting task given all the different levels of authority that are responsible for administering a degree program. Luckily, the academic advisors at McMaster are more than happy to provide you with advice to help you complete your double degree. It is important to speak with an academic advisor once you have chosen majors for your double degree in order to find out more about the permissibility of your major combination (not all combinations of majors are allowed) as well as clarify any misconceptions you may have about the relevant policies surrounding your majors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Choose Your Double Degree Majors</title>
      <link>https://kelvinlin.com/blog/how-to-choose-your-double-degree-majors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 21:48:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kelvinlin.com/blog/how-to-choose-your-double-degree-majors/</guid>
      <description>Source: Unsplash.
Choosing your major can be one of the most important yet stressful decisions you make during your undergraduate career. Your majors will dictate the courses you need to take, the academic policies you need to follow, and what your transcripts and degrees will list when you graduate. Doing a double degree means you have (at least) twice as many majors - but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be twice as stressful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Get a Double Degree at McMaster University</title>
      <link>https://kelvinlin.com/blog/how-to-get-a-double-degree-at-mcmaster-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 18:43:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kelvinlin.com/blog/how-to-get-a-double-degree-at-mcmaster-university/</guid>
      <description>Source: Unsplash.
Getting a double degree at McMaster isn&amp;rsquo;t easy. Double degrees (otherwise known as concurrent second bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degrees) are not formally defined by the university, very few students pursue double degrees, and the onus is ultimately on you to determine the path you need to take in order to successfully complete all of the degree requirements.
Having recently graduated with concurrent double degrees in Software Engineering &amp;amp; Management as well as Economics, I hope to create a blog to help others do the same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://kelvinlin.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 16:25:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kelvinlin.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>  
Want to contact me? Email me at kelvinlin (at) gatech.edu, send me a message on LinkedIn, or fill out the form below, and I&amp;rsquo;ll get back to you as soon as I can.
Please do not contact me with unsolicited services or marketing. I do not host guest articles on my blog. I do not provide tutoring services or academic counselling.
Loading... </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy</title>
      <link>https://kelvinlin.com/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 16:25:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kelvinlin.com/privacy/</guid>
      <description>1. General Policy Your privacy is important to me. It is my policy to respect your privacy regarding any information I may collect from you across my website, https://kelvinlin.com.
I only ask for personal information when we truly need it to provide a service to you. I collect it by fair and lawful means, with your knowledge and consent. I also let you know why I&amp;rsquo;m collecting it and how it will be used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses</title>
      <link>https://kelvinlin.com/courses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 17:23:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kelvinlin.com/courses/</guid>
      <description>Georgia Institute of Technology (Georgia Tech) The following is a list of courses that I took at the Georgia Tech.
  
Computer Science (11 courses)   Course Code Course Name     CS 6250 Computer Networks   CS 6515 Introduction to Graduate Algorithms   CS 6601 Artificial Intelligence   CS 6603 AI, Ethics, and Society   CS 7632 Game AI   CS 7638 Robotics: AI Techniques   CS 7641 Machine Learning   CS 7643 Deep Learning   CS 7646 Machine Learning for Trading   CS 8801 Artificial Intelligence Reading Group   CS 8801 Research Seminar      Industrial &amp; Systems Engineering (1 course)   Course Code Course Name     ISYE 6420 Bayesian Statistics</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awards and Certificates</title>
      <link>https://kelvinlin.com/awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 16:23:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kelvinlin.com/awards/</guid>
      <description>Here are a selection of awards and certificates that I&amp;rsquo;ve received from work, school, and participating in programming and engineering competitions.
MOOCs (3 certificates) Artificial Intelligence Nanodegree    School: Udacity My AI nanodegree covered probabilistic AI, game-playing agents, search algorithms, neural networks, deep learning, and a specialization in NLP. The syllabus for this nanodegree can be found here.    M101J: MongoDB for Java Developers    School: MongoDB University M101J covered topics such as no-SQL databases, MongoDB&#39;s document model and basic schema design, MongoDB CRUD operations, and how to read and write to a MongoDB database using Java.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://kelvinlin.com/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 18:15:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kelvinlin.com/projects/</guid>
      <description>Here are some projects that I am proud to have worked on. Other projects can be found on my Github at: https://github.com/KelvinKKLin. Project Imacs    A non-linear text editor/file visualization tool created for my Software Engineering capstone at McMaster University - Recieved A+.
Technologies Used: HTML/CSS, TypeScript, Electron, D3, Hyperapp    Parallel N-Body Simulator    A n-particle physics simulator that models the interaction between up to 32,000 particles in empty space - Received A+.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://kelvinlin.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 14:44:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kelvinlin.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello world, I&amp;rsquo;m Kelvin - a recent Master of Science in Computer Science graduate from Georgia Tech. I LOVE engineering impactful software systems that make the world a better place while empowering others to do the same. More details about my work experiences and qualifications can be found on LinkedIn at https://linkedin.com/in/kelvin-lin. 
Education See Courses  Master of Science in Computer Science (Specialization in Machine Learning)
GPA: 4.0/4.0 ; simultaneously completed the requirements for a specialization in Interactive Intelligence.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>