<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SE&amp;M on Kelvin Lin</title>
    <link>https://kelvinlin.com/tags/sem/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SE&amp;M on Kelvin Lin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Kelvin Lin © 2022</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 22:48:01 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kelvinlin.com/tags/sem/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>COMPSCI 4ML3: An Honest Review</title>
      <link>https://kelvinlin.com/blog/compsci-4ml3-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 22:48:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kelvinlin.com/blog/compsci-4ml3-review/</guid>
      <description>I recently completed McMaster&amp;rsquo;s inaugural offering of COMPSCI 4ML3: Introduction to Machine Learning taught by Dr. Hassan Ashtiani. Motivated by my enthusiasm for machine learning as well as lack of reviews of this course, I wanted to write a quick blog post to describe my experience in this course for students who are looking to take this course in the future.
An example of an artificial neural network, one of the algorithms discussed in COMPSCI 4ML3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Honest Thoughts on McMaster&#39;s Software Engineering and Management Program</title>
      <link>https://kelvinlin.com/blog/3-honest-thoughts-on-mcmasters-software-engineering-and-management-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 23:10:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kelvinlin.com/blog/3-honest-thoughts-on-mcmasters-software-engineering-and-management-program/</guid>
      <description>A couple of days ago, McMaster released degree program placements to incoming second-year students, which will determine the course of study for many students for the remainder of their degree (unless the student decides to transfer or pursue a double degree). This is a time filled with excitement, worry, anticipation, and perhaps disappointment, but seeing as there are very few reviews of the Software Engineering and Management (Co-op) program that I recently graduated from, I have decided to start a blog series documenting my own personal thoughts on the program.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>