<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Kelvin Lin</title>
    <link>https://kelvinlin.ca/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Kelvin Lin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 23:10:01 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kelvinlin.ca/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Honest Thoughts on McMaster&#39;s Software Engineering and Management Program</title>
      <link>https://kelvinlin.ca/blog/software-engineering-and-management-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 23:10:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kelvinlin.ca/blog/software-engineering-and-management-overview/</guid>
      <description>A couple of days ago, McMaster released degree program placements to incoming second-year students, which will determine the course of study for many students for the remainder of their degree (unless the student decides to transfer or pursue a double degree). This is a time filled with excitement, worry, anticipation, and perhaps disappointment, but seeing as there are very few reviews of the Software Engineering and Management (Co-op) program that I recently graduated from, I have decided to start a blog series documenting my own personal thoughts on the program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Create a Master Plan for Your Double Degree</title>
      <link>https://kelvinlin.ca/blog/how-to-create-a-master-plan-for-your-double-degree/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 23:04:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kelvinlin.ca/blog/how-to-create-a-master-plan-for-your-double-degree/</guid>
      <description>Once you&amp;rsquo;ve received the go-ahead from your academic advisor, it is time to start planning out your McMaster double degree. When planning your degrees, start with the end goal in mind. Ask yourself what you would like to have achieved by graduation. Starting with the end goal in mind ensures that you will take the most appropriate courses for your degrees (and have the proper prerequisite courses to enroll in upper-year classes), so you can get the most out of your double degree journey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Talk to Your Academic Advisors about Your Double Degree</title>
      <link>https://kelvinlin.ca/blog/how-to-talk-to-your-academic-advisors-about-your-double-degree/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 22:34:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kelvinlin.ca/blog/how-to-talk-to-your-academic-advisors-about-your-double-degree/</guid>
      <description>Source: Unsplash
Navigating university bureaucracy can be a daunting task given all the different levels of authority that are responsible for administering a degree program. Luckily, the academic advisors at McMaster are more than happy to provide you with advice to help you complete your double degree. It is important to speak with an academic advisor once you have chosen majors for your double degree in order to find out more about the permissibility of your major combination (not all combinations of majors are allowed) as well as clarify any misconceptions you may have about the relevant policies surrounding your majors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Choose Your Double Degree Majors</title>
      <link>https://kelvinlin.ca/blog/how-to-choose-your-double-degree-majors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 21:48:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kelvinlin.ca/blog/how-to-choose-your-double-degree-majors/</guid>
      <description>Source: Unsplash
Choosing your major can be one of the most important yet stressful decisions you make during your undergraduate career. Your majors will dictate the courses you need to take, the academic policies you need to follow, and what your transcripts and degrees will list when you graduate. Doing a double degree means you have (at least) twice as many majors - but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be twice as stressful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Get a Double Degree at McMaster University</title>
      <link>https://kelvinlin.ca/blog/how-to-get-a-double-degree-at-mcmaster-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 18:43:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kelvinlin.ca/blog/how-to-get-a-double-degree-at-mcmaster-university/</guid>
      <description>Source: Unsplash
Getting a double degree at McMaster isn&amp;rsquo;t easy. Double degrees (otherwise known as concurrent second bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degrees) are not formally defined by the university, very few students pursue double degrees, and the onus is ultimately on you to determine the path you need to take in order to successfully complete all of the degree requirements.
Having recently graduated with concurrent double degrees in Software Engineering &amp;amp; Management as well as Economics, I hope to create a blog to help others do the same.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>